<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A president for purchasers, sellers and mortgagers, or, Anatocisme (commonly called compound interest) made easie, without arithmetical calculation by a table ready computed, by which may be known the real worth of any annuity, rent or pension, either in present possession or in reversion (to be paid annually) at six pounds in the computed by W. Leybourn.</title>
            <author>Leybourn, William, 1626-1716.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1678</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 45 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A48353</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L1933</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R4150</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12413815</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12413815</idno>
            <idno type="VID">61617</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A48353)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 61617)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 282:11)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A president for purchasers, sellers and mortgagers, or, Anatocisme (commonly called compound interest) made easie, without arithmetical calculation by a table ready computed, by which may be known the real worth of any annuity, rent or pension, either in present possession or in reversion (to be paid annually) at six pounds in the computed by W. Leybourn.</title>
                  <author>Leybourn, William, 1626-1716.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for William Jacob ... and Langley Curtis ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1678.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Interest rates --  Tables.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="treatise">
            <pb facs="tcp:61617:1"/>
            <head>A Preſident for Purchaſers, Sellers and Mortgagers: <hi>OR, ANATOCISME</hi> (commonly called <hi>Compound Intereſt</hi>) MADE EASIE; without Arithmetical Calculation: By a <hi>TABLE</hi> ready Computed. By which may be known the real Worth of any Annuity, Rent or Penſion; either in preſent Poſſeſſion, or in Reverſion (to be paid Annually) at Six Pounds in the Hundred (Intereſt upon Intereſt). From One Year, to an Hundred Years; and from 20 s. a year, to 100, 500, 1000 l. a year; and upward; onely by common Addition.</head>
            <byline>Computed by <hi>W. Leybourn.</hi>
            </byline>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <head>The Number of the, Years to be Purchaſed.</head>
                  <row>
                     <cell cols="35">
                        <hi>The number of Pounds a Year to be Purchased.</hi>
                     </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell cols="3">1</cell>
                     <cell cols="3">2</cell>
                     <cell cols="3">3</cell>
                     <cell cols="3">4</cell>
                     <cell cols="3">5</cell>
                     <cell cols="3">10</cell>
                     <cell cols="3">20</cell>
                     <cell cols="3">30</cell>
                     <cell cols="3">40</cell>
                     <cell cols="3">50</cell>
                     <cell cols="3">100</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>l.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>l.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>l.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>l.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>l.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>l.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>l.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>l.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>l.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>l.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>l.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>28</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>37</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>47</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>94</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>32</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>49</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>64</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>80</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>161</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>26</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>53</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>80</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>106</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>133</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>367</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>34</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>69</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>103</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>138</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>173</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>346</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>21</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>42</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>84</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>126</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>168</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>210</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>421</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>19</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>24</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>40</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>98</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>147</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>196</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>245</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>491</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>22</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>27</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>55</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>111</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>167</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>223</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>278</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>01</cell>
                     <cell>556</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>24</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>31</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>62</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>124</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>186</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>248</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>310</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>620</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>20</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>27</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>34</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>68</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>136</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>204</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>272</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>330</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>660</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>22</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>29</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>36</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>73</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>147</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>220</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>294</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>367</cell>
                     <cell>19</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>735</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>23</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>31</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>39</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>78</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>157</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>236</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>315</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>394</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>788</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>25</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>33</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>41</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>83</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>167</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>251</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>334</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>418</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>837</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>26</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>35</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>44</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>88</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>177</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>265</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>354</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>442</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>885</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>27</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>37</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>46</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>92</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>185</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>278</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>371</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>464</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>929</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>19</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>29</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>38</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>48</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>97</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>194</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>291</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>388</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>485</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>971</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>20</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>30</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>40</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>50</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>101</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>202</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>303</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>404</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>505</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>1010</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>20</cell>
                     <cell>19</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>31</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>41</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>52</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>104</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>209</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>314</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>419</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>523</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>1047</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>21</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>32</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>43</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>54</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>108</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>216</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>324</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>433</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>541</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>1082</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>19</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>22</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>33</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>44</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>55</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>111</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>223</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>334</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>446</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>557</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>1115</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>20</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>22</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>34</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>45</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>57</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>114</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>229</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>344</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>458</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>573</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>1146</cell>
                     <cell>19</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>21</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>23</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>35</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>47</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>58</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>117</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>235</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>352</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>470</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>588</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>1176</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>22</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>24</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>36</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>48</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>60</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>120</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>240</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>361</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>481</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>602</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>1204</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>23</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>24</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>36</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>49</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>61</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>123</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>246</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>361</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>492</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>615</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>1230</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>24</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>25</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>37</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>50</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>62</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>125</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>251</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>376</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>502</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>627</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>1255</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>22</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>25</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>38</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>51</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>63</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>127</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>255</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>383</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>511</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>639</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>1278</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>26</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>26</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>39</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>52</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>65</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>130</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>260</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>390</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>520</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>650</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>1300</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>27</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>26</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>39</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>52</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>66</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>132</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>264</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>396</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>528</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>660</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>1321</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>28</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>26</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>40</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>53</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>67</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>134</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>268</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>402</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>536</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>670</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>1340</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>29</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>27</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>40</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>54</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>67</cell>
                     <cell>19</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>135</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>271</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>407</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>543</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>679</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>1359</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>30</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>27</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>41</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>55</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>68</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>137</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>275</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>412</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>550</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>688</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>1376</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>40</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>30</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>45</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>60</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>75</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>150</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>300</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>450</cell>
                     <cell>19</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>601</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>750</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>1501</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>50</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>31</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>47</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>62</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>78</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>157</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>314</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>471</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>629</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>786</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>1572</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>60</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>32</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>48</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>64</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>80</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>161</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>323</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>484</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>646</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>808</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>1616</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>70</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>32</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>49</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>65</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>81</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>163</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>327</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>491</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>655</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>819</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>1638</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>80</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>33</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>49</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>66</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>82</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>165</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>330</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>495</cell>
                     <cell>5</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>660</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>825</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>1650</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>90</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>33</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>49</cell>
                     <cell>14</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>66</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>82</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>165</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>331</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>497</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>663</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>828</cell>
                     <cell>19</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>1657</cell>
                     <cell>18</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>100</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>33</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>49</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>66</cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>83</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>166</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>332</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>498</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>664</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>830</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>1661</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <div type="part">
               <head>The uſe of the TABLE Exem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plified, in the Reſolving of ſeveral QUESTIONS.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Queſt. I.</hi> What is a Leaſe, Annuity, Rent or Penſion of <hi>30 l.</hi> a Year, and to continue <hi>13</hi> years, worth in ready money, at <hi>6 per cent.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>YOu muſt firſt find 13. (the number of years to be purchaſed) in the firſt Column of the <hi>Years,</hi> towards the Left-hand (under the word Tabl;) Then look along that Line (towards the Right-hand) till you come under the Fi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gure 30 at the Head of the Table (which is the Annuity <hi>per Annum</hi> to be purchaſed) and right againſt 13, and under 30, you ſhall find 265 l. 11 s. 3 d. And ſo much is an Annuity, Leaſe, Rent or Penſion of 30 l. a year, and to conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nue 13 years, worth in preſent Money, the Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſer having 6 <hi>per Cent.</hi> Compound Intereſt, Profit for his Money laying out.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Queſt. II.</hi> What Money will Purchaſe an An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuity, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of <hi>5 l.</hi> a Year, and to continue <hi>21</hi> Years, at <hi>6 per Cent.</hi> Compound Intereſt?</p>
               <p>LOok for 21 years in the firſt Column to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards your Left-hand, and in the ſame Line towards the Right-hand, under 5, in the Head of the Table, you ſhall find 58 l. 16 s. 4 d. And ſo much Money will purchaſe a Leaſe or Annuity of 5 l. a year for 21 years, and 6 in the Hundred Intereſt upon Intereſt being allowed.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Queſt. III.</hi> What is a Leaſe, Annuity, Rent or Penſion of <hi>43 l.</hi> a Year, and to continue <hi>30</hi> Tears, worth in ready Money?</p>
               <p>FOraſmuch as the Number 43 cannot be found in the Head of the Table, you muſt therefore reſolve the Queſtion at two Operati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, in this manner:</p>
               <p n="1">1. Find 30 in the Firſt Column, and along that Line under 40, you ſhall find — 550 l. 11 s. — 8 d.</p>
               <p n="2">2. Find 30 in the Firſt Column, and againſt it under 3 in the Head of the Table, you ſhall find 45 l. — 01 s. — 10 d Which added to the former, makes 595 l. 13 s. 6 d. And ſo much is a Leaſe, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of 43 l. a year, and to continue 30 years, worth in preſent Money.</p>
               <p>And thus you ſhall find that an Annuity, Rent or Penſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of
<list>
                     <head>Lib.</head>
                     <item>
                        <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>8</item>
                     <item>17</item>
                     <item>22</item>
                     <item>37</item>
                     <item>45</item>
                     <item>58</item>
                  </list>
Pounds a Year, and to continue
<list>
                     <head>Yea.</head>
                     <item>23</item>
                     <item>17</item>
                     <item>25</item>
                     <item>8</item>
                     <item>11</item>
                     <item>27</item>
                  </list>
Will be worth in preſent Mo.
<table>
                     <row>
                        <cell>l.</cell>
                        <cell>s.</cell>
                        <cell>d.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>14<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>14</cell>
                        <cell>04</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>178</cell>
                        <cell>02</cell>
                        <cell>02</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>281</cell>
                        <cell>04</cell>
                        <cell>08</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>272</cell>
                        <cell>01</cell>
                        <cell>09</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>354</cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>766</cell>
                        <cell>04</cell>
                        <cell>01</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Queſt. IV.</hi> What is a Leaſe or Annuity, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of <hi>146 l.</hi> a year, and to continue <hi>50</hi> years, w<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>th in preſent Money?</p>
               <p>BY the Rules above delivered, you may find, by the Table, that
<table>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>l.</cell>
                        <cell>s.</cell>
                        <cell>d.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>100 l. for 50 years is worth</cell>
                        <cell>1572</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>40 l. for 50 years is worth</cell>
                        <cell>0629</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>05 l. for 50 years is worth</cell>
                        <cell>0078</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>06</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>03 l. for 50 years is worth</cell>
                        <cell>0047</cell>
                        <cell>03</cell>
                        <cell>06</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>148 l. for 50 years is worth therefore—</cell>
                        <cell>2327</cell>
                        <cell>06</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Queſt. V.</hi> Two Perſons <hi>M.</hi> and <hi>S.</hi> have either of them a Leaſe, which, for convenience, they would exchange, — <hi>M.</hi> his Leaſe brings him in clear <hi>30 l.</hi> a Year, and is in being <hi>21</hi> years; <hi>S.</hi> his Leaſe brings in clear <hi>40 l.</hi> a year, and he hath <hi>16</hi> years to come: Which Leaſe is woth moſt?</p>
               <p>BY the Table you may find that M. his Leaſe of 30 l. a year for 21 years, will be worth but 352 l.— 18 s.— 1 d. And by the Table alſo you may find that S. his Leaſe of 40 l. a year for 16 years will be worth —404 l.—04 s.—02 d The difference is—051 l.—06 s.—01 d. And ſo much is the Leaſe of S. better than the Leaſe of M.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Queſt. VI.</hi> A perſon having <hi>300 l.</hi> lying by him, with which he would willingly purchaſe an Annuity of <hi>20 l.</hi> a year; for how many years will that Money purchaſe ſuch an Annuity?</p>
               <p>YOu muſt look for 20 (the Annual Annuity) at the Head of the Table, and look down that Column till you find the Sum 300 l. (or the neareſt to it) and the number of years (in the firſt Column) which ſtand againſt that Sum, is the number of years that Sum of Money will purchaſe 20 l. a year for.</p>
               <p>Thus if you find 20 in the Head of the Table, and look down that Column, you cannot find juſt 300 l. but the neareſt to it is 300 l. — 12 s. — 4 d. Againſt which, in the firſt Column, there ſtands 40. So that if he add 12 s.— 4 d. more to this 300 l. It will purchaſe him an Annuity of 20 l. a year for 40 years.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Queſt. VII.</hi> A Landlord having a Leaſe of a Houſe which brings him in <hi>127 l.</hi> a Year clear; He having a preſent occaſion for a Sum of Money, deſires ſo much of his Tenant as will countervail <hi>7</hi> years Rent, and he will allow him after the Rate of <hi>6 per Cent.</hi> Compound Intereſt for his Money: How much Money may he lend?</p>
               <p>BY the Table and the Directions before gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven, you may find that a Leaſe of
<table>
                     <row>
                        <cell rows="2">100 l. a year for 7 years is worth —</cell>
                        <cell>l.</cell>
                        <cell>s.</cell>
                        <cell>d.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>556</cell>
                        <cell>02</cell>
                        <cell>02</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>20 l. a year for 7 years is worth</cell>
                        <cell>111</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>5 l. a year for 7 years is worth</cell>
                        <cell>027</cell>
                        <cell>18</cell>
                        <cell>03</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>2 l. a year for 7 years is worth</cell>
                        <cell>011</cell>
                        <cell>03</cell>
                        <cell>03</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>127 l. a year for 7 years is worth</cell>
                        <cell>706</cell>
                        <cell>16</cell>
                        <cell>06</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
And ſo much may the Tenant lend, and have 6. <hi>per Cent.</hi> Compound Intereſt.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Queſt. VIII.</hi> If a Leaſe of <hi>30 l.</hi> a year, and a <hi>100 l.</hi> Fine, is to be let for <hi>21</hi> years, what Fine muſt be given to bring the Rent down to <hi>10 l.</hi> a year?</p>
               <p>FIrſt, find the Difference between the Rent demanded (<hi>Viz.</hi> 30 l.) and the Rent de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſired (<hi>Viz.</hi> 10 l.) which difference is 20 l.— Secondly, Find by the Table what 20 l. a year is worth for 21 years, which you ſhall find to be 235 l. 5 s. 5 d. to which add 100 l. (the Fine demanded) and the Sum will be 335 l.—5 s.—5 d. And ſuch Fine muſt be paid to bring the Rent down to 10 l. a year.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Queſt. IX.</hi> One hath a Leaſe of a Houſe for <hi>30</hi> years, for the firſt <hi>10</hi> years he is to pay <hi>15 l.</hi> a year, and for the remaining <hi>20</hi> years, he is to pay <hi>20 l.</hi> a year: What is this Leaſe worth in ready Money?</p>
               <p>BY the Table you may find that 20 l. a year for 30 years is worth 275 l.—5 s.—10 d. Now (becauſe 5 l. a year is to be abated for the firſt 10 years) find what 5 l. a year is worth for 10 years, which you will find to be 36 l. 15 s.—11 d. which being ſubſtracted from 275 l.—5 s.—10 d. the remainder will be 233 l.—9 s.—11 d. for the preſent worth of the Leaſe.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Queſt. X.</hi> Demand is made for a Leaſe of a Houſe for <hi>21</hi> years, <hi>10 l.</hi> a year, and <hi>335 l.—5 s. — 5 d.</hi> Fine, the Tenant is willing to give <hi>100 l.</hi> Fine, and an increaſe of Rent pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portionably to the Abatement of the Fine: What Rent muſt Annually be paid?</p>
               <p>THe Fine Demanded is 335 l.—5 s.—5 d. and the Fine offered is 100 l. The Differ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence is 235 l.—5 s.— 5 d. Look in the Table for 21 years (the Term of the Leaſe) in the firſt Column toward the Left-hand, then caſt your Eye along that Line till you come to find 235 l. — 5 s. — 5 d. (or the neareſt Sum to it) which you ſhall find to ſtand under 20 l. in the Head of the Table: Which ſhews, that he muſt advance 20 l. a year in his Rent, to bring down the Fine demanded (<hi>Viz.</hi> 335 l. 5 s.— 5 d.) to a 100 l. And ſo for his Leaſe of 21 years, he muſt pay 30 l. a year and a 100 l. Fine.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>A Second TABLE, ſhewing the preſent Worth and Value of any LEASE or ANNUITY for any Number of Years, from One to an Hundred: And at all theſe ſeveral Rates of Compound Intereſt; <hi>Viz.</hi> 6 l. 8 l. and 10 l. <hi>per Cent. per Annum.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <row>
                        <cell cols="2">The Number of Years to be purchaſed.</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>4</cell>
                        <cell>5</cell>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                        <cell>7</cell>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>13</cell>
                        <cell>14</cell>
                        <cell>15</cell>
                        <cell>16</cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>18</cell>
                        <cell>19</cell>
                        <cell>20</cell>
                        <cell>21</cell>
                        <cell>22</cell>
                        <cell>23</cell>
                        <cell>24</cell>
                        <cell>25</cell>
                        <cell>26</cell>
                        <cell>27</cell>
                        <cell>28</cell>
                        <cell>29</cell>
                        <cell>30</cell>
                        <cell>31</cell>
                        <cell>41</cell>
                        <cell>51</cell>
                        <cell>61</cell>
                        <cell>71</cell>
                        <cell>81</cell>
                        <cell>91</cell>
                        <cell cols="2">Fee-ſimple.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell rows="3">At V. <hi>per Cent.</hi> For the Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſe of Freehold Land.</cell>
                        <cell>Years</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>4</cell>
                        <cell>5</cell>
                        <cell>5</cell>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                        <cell>7</cell>
                        <cell>7</cell>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>13</cell>
                        <cell>13</cell>
                        <cell>13</cell>
                        <cell>14</cell>
                        <cell>14</cell>
                        <cell>14</cell>
                        <cell>15</cell>
                        <cell>15</cell>
                        <cell>15</cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>18</cell>
                        <cell>18</cell>
                        <cell>19</cell>
                        <cell>19</cell>
                        <cell>19</cell>
                        <cell>20</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Quarters</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Moneths</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1¼</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1¼</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>½</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell rows="3">At VI. <hi>per Cent.</hi> For the pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſe of Copyhold Land, or Leaſes of Land.</cell>
                        <cell>Years</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>4</cell>
                        <cell>4</cell>
                        <cell>5</cell>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                        <cell>7</cell>
                        <cell>7</cell>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>13</cell>
                        <cell>13</cell>
                        <cell>13</cell>
                        <cell>13</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>13</cell>
                        <cell>15</cell>
                        <cell>15</cell>
                        <cell>16</cell>
                        <cell>16</cell>
                        <cell>16</cell>
                        <cell>16</cell>
                        <cell>16</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Quarters</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Moneths</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2¼</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>½</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>2½</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>½</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell rows="3">At VIII. <hi>per Cent.</hi> For the pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſe of Leaſes of Land, and very good Houſes.</cell>
                        <cell>Years</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>4</cell>
                        <cell>4</cell>
                        <cell>5</cell>
                        <cell>5</cell>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                        <cell>7</cell>
                        <cell>7</cell>
                        <cell>7</cell>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell>12</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Quarters</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Moneths</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2¼</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell rows="3">At X. <hi>per Cent.</hi> For the pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſe of Leaſes of ordinary Houſes.</cell>
                        <cell>Years</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>4</cell>
                        <cell>4</cell>
                        <cell>5</cell>
                        <cell>5</cell>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                        <cell>7</cell>
                        <cell>7</cell>
                        <cell>7</cell>
                        <cell>7</cell>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Quarters</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Moneths</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1½</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1½</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1½</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>THe Uſe of this TABLE is very plain and eaſie; as by Examples following ſhall be made appear.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Queſt. I.</hi> What is a Leaſe of <hi>20</hi> years of Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold Land worth in ready Money, at <hi>5 per C</hi>
               </p>
               <p>LOok in the Head of the Table among the Great Figures for 20 (the Number of years to be purchaſed, and underneath 20, you ſhall find 12 l.—1 s. —2 d. that is 12 years, 1 quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter and 2 Moneths Rent, ſo that if the Rent were 10 l. a year, the Leaſe would be worth 10 times 12 l. that is 120 l. and the Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter of the year will be 2 l-10 s.-and the 2 Moneths will be worth 1 l. 13 s. 4 d. all which being added together will make 124 l. 3 s. 4 d. for the worth of the Leaſe for 20 years at 5 l. in the Hundred.</p>
               <p>But if the Purchaſer will have 6 l. profit for his Money, then the Purchaſe will be worth but 11 years 1 quart. &amp; 2½ Moneths. Or if he would make 8 in the 100 profit for his Money, then it will be worth but 9 years, 3 quarters and 2 Moneths purchaſe.</p>
               <p>And farther, If he will have 10 l. in the Hundred profit for his Money laying out, it will be worth but 8 years, a half and 1 1/<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>; Moneths Rent: And ſo for any other Number of years.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Queſt. II.</hi> What is an Annuity of <hi>25 l.</hi> a year to continue <hi>31</hi> years, worth in ready Money at <hi>5, 6, 8,</hi> and <hi>10 l.</hi> in the Hundred.</p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>Years</cell>
                        <cell>Quart.</cell>
                        <cell>Moneths.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell rows="4">A Leaſe for 31 years, at</cell>
                        <cell>5</cell>
                        <cell rows="4">
                           <hi>Per Cent.</hi> is worth</cell>
                        <cell>15</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell rows="4">Purchaſe.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                        <cell>13</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>09</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>And thus, the Rent being 25 l. a year,
<table>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>l.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>l.</cell>
                        <cell>s.</cell>
                        <cell>d.</cell>
                        <cell>q.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell rows="4">At</cell>
                        <cell>5</cell>
                        <cell rows="4">
                           <hi>Per Cent.</hi> the Purchaſe will be worth</cell>
                        <cell>394</cell>
                        <cell>04</cell>
                        <cell>08</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                        <cell>346</cell>
                        <cell>05</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>282</cell>
                        <cell>09</cell>
                        <cell>02</cell>
                        <cell>03</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>243</cell>
                        <cell>15</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>And theſe Two Examples are ſufficient for the Uſe of this TABLE.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="license">
            <p>Licenſed <hi>Jan.</hi> 25. 1677/8, <hi>Rog. L'Eſtrange.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>William Jacob,</hi> at the <hi>Black Swan</hi> in <hi>Holborn</hi>; And <hi>Langley Curtis</hi> in <hi>Goat-Court</hi> upon <hi>Ludgate-Hill.</hi> 1678. ☞ <hi>And at the</hi> Black Swan <hi>is Made and Sold the beſt Ink for DEEDS and RECORDS.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
